premierinn.com 2017-11-15

# Privacy Policy | Premier Inn

1\. General

Premier Inn respects the right to privacy of every individual who visits our site, mobile site or apps ("Digital Channels"). This privacy policy explains how we use any personal information we collect about you, and your rights to access and correct the personal information we hold about you.

2\. What personal information do we collect and how we will use it?

We may collect the following information about you:

  * Contact details including title, name, postal and email addresses, postcode, contact telephone numbers;
  * Business information, such as employer details and job title, particularly from our corporate customers;
  * Transaction information, including payment and reservation and booking details;
  * Your membership of Whitbread group company (see further information) rewards programmes and Premier Inn Business Account membership and participation details (including birthdays and special dates where you provide this information to us and preferred restaurant locations);
  * Purchase history, including the hotels that you have stayed in, activities on site (e.g. food purchases and  Wi-Fi use) and the date(s) of your stay;
  * Demographic information;
  * Registration information, including your password and room and other expressed preferences;
  * Customer communication preferences;
  * Customer feedback; and
  * Computer or device information (e.g. your IP address and operating system).

We may supplement the information that you provide to us with information from trusted third parties (including travel agencies, distributors and list rental companies) for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy.

Where you book accommodation for other people, we may ask you to provide the above information about them (e.g. we will usually ask for the title, first name and surname, e-mail address and nationality of a person for each room that you book for identification purposes). You should only provide us with information about other people if you have their permission to do so.

We may use your information for the following purposes:

  * Administration and management of room and restaurant bookings and our hotels and restaurants;
  * Processing transactions;
  * Administration of our Digital Channels, including in respect of our registered users, who may also store a personal identification number online to easily access and apply room preferences and personal details when booking through our automated telephone service;
  * Administration and management of our competitions, promotions and prize draws – you should check the applicable terms and conditions of the competition, promotion or prize draw for further information;
  * Sending you communications about our products and services that we think may be of interest to you. We may also send you service information communications (e.g. reservation/booking confirmation). With your permission, we and other companies in the Whitbread group (see further information) will keep you informed of news and offers from other Whitbread group companies;
  * Business, website and consumer analysis and reporting; and
  * Correspondence between us, including where you use our 'Contact us' form.

3\. Sharing your personal information with third parties

We may disclose your personal information to (in so far this is in line with applicable local data protection laws):

  * Other companies in the Whitbread group (see further information) and to service providers for the purposes outlined above;
  * A buyer in the event that we or any of our assets are acquired by a third party (as your information may be one of the transferring assets); and/or
  * Any third party where we are under a legal duty to do so, or in order to enforce or protect any of our rights, property or safety (or those of our customers). This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Where personal information is processed on our behalf by third parties (such as for the purposes of processing your room booking), we put measures in place to keep your information secure.

Our Digital Channels contain links to other websites, mobile sites and apps. This privacy policy only applies to our channels. When you link to other websites, mobile sites or apps we are not responsible or liable for them. You should read the privacy policies for those linked sites or apps before you submit any personal information to them.

4\. Cookies

Our Digital Channels use cookies, which are small text files that contain small amounts of information that a website can send to, and store on, your computer or device through your browser. Cookies may be used by us to provide you with, for example, customised information from our website to make it more user-friendly.

For further details about the cookies on our Digital Channels, please see our ‘[How we use cookies](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/terms/how-we-use-cookies.html)’ statement.

By using our Digital Channels, you agree to our privacy and [cookie](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/terms/how-we-use-cookies.html) policies and consent to the use of cookies and similar technologies by us and our carefully selected third party partners as described in these policies. If you do not agree to such use, please see the ['Managing your cookies' section](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/terms/how-we-use-cookies.html) for details on how to adjust your settings.

5\. Security

Premier Inn takes the security of any personal information we hold very seriously.

Where necessary, and in common with other websites and apps, we use SSL (Secure Sockets Layer) encryption to ensure that personal information provided to us is not visible to anybody else when in transit between your computer and our servers. You can tell when SSL is in use by the presence of a small "padlock" symbol in the status bar of your web browser.

In addition, our web servers are housed behind a secure firewall that prevents access to our databases by unauthorised users. All of our servers are housed in a secure environment with high levels of physical security.

However, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. We cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site: any transmission is at your risk. Once we have received your information, we will handle it in accordance with our usual practices.

Where you have chosen a password that enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

6\. International transfers

We may transfer your personal information to, and store it at, destinations outside of the European Economic Area ("EEA") for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy. It may be processed by staff operating outside the EEA who work for us, for the Whitbread group of companies (see further information) or our service providers. By submitting your personal information, you agree to this transfer.

Premier Inn will take appropriate measures to ensure that, wherever it is located, your personal information is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.

7\. Direct marketing

We would like to keep you informed of Premier Inn news and offers by post, phone, email, text and other electronic means.

We and other companies in the Whitbread group (see further information) would also like to keep you informed of news and offers from other Whitbread brands (including hub by Premier Inn, Beefeater, Brewers Fayre, Taybarns and Table Table restaurants and Costa) by post, phone, email, text and other electronic means.

If you have agreed to receive such marketing communications you may opt out or change your marketing preferences at any time by [contacting us](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/contact-us.html). If you have registered with Premier Inn you can change your preferences in the [My Premier Inn](https://secure.premierinn.com/en/mypremierinn/home.action) section on this site.

8\. Access to and amending your personal information

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove personal information you think is inaccurate by [contacting us](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/contact-us.html). If you are registered with Premier Inn you can also update your contact details and other personal information in the [My Premier Inn](https://secure.premierinn.com/en/mypremierinn/home.action) section of this site.

You also have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold about you. To do so, please [contact us](https://www.premierinn.com/gb/en/contact-us.html). We may make a small charge for this service.

9\. Changes to our Privacy Policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on our Digital Channels.

10\. Contact us

If you require further information or have any questions regarding this Privacy Policy, then please email us at guest.relations@premierinn.com, telephone us on 0333 003 0025 or write to us at:

Premier Inn Guest Relations  
Oakley House  
Oakley Road  
Leagrave  
Luton  
Bedfordshire  
LU4 9QH

11\. Further information

This site is operated by Premier Inn Hotels Limited (company number 05137608 and VAT number 243292864) whose registered office is Whitbread Court, Houghton Hall Business Park, Porz Avenue, Dunstable LU5 5XE. Premier Inn is a member of the Whitbread group of companies.  

The principal operating companies of the Whitbread group include:

  * Whitbread Group plc (company number 00029423)
  * Premier Inn Ochre Limited (company number 08143826)
  * Costa Limited (company number 01270695)
  * Costa Express Limited (company number 03145187)
